[Music]
dai shi maat Lima peed on us
so I grew up on Long Island New York
as a young child there was a TV show
called Andy's gang the scene song was
God again everybody's good old Andy's
gang and they feature drama of the
jungle adaptations of Rudyard Kipling
and the boy Rama had just a gunshot yeah
turned them no shoes hung out in all
these temples in Bengali when he would
go to the temple he was here then
chanting Hari Krishna Krishna Krishna
Krishna Hari Rama
that was my first exposure to Krishna
consciousness now when I was in high
school probably tenth grade I guess
tenth grade a friend of mine a good
friend of mine
I had gone to castings school so I grew
up as a Catholic so a good friend of
mine Peter Campanella was in New York
City he came across historical
bachelor's gifts he bought a copy of an
album
we're probably chanting Hari Krishna
radhe Krishna Krishna Krishna
[Music]
he brought this album home and called us
all up and said you guys are not gonna
believe what I found
he said what he said I got a
transmission here from a spaceman this
guy is out from outer space he's brought
a message I don't know if anybody's
deciphered it yet but he brought a
message and if you listen to him chant
you will go into ecstasy and do the
dance of ecstasy so we were all a little
white guys and little punks but we
thought how we gonna pass up listen to a
spaceman so we all got together and we
were smoking some hashish capitalist
house he had bongo drums and cymbals and
we started chanting and by the time the
chanting over we were in ecstasy and so
I still have the hardy krishna album and
so these guys had I store in Laguna
called the Brotherhood of eternal love
and they had they had a juice bar in the
bookstore and and a place you could sell
clothes and in the back they had a
meditation room and another guy who was
working there as it was Nandu Kumar he
and I became good friends we go in there
one day and here they are in the back
room Shankar
I had no idea anybody knew about sharing
car worship with us but we went back in
and dinner nos was there tomorrow
krishna was there several other devotees
were there they told us all about the
temple and that we had to go so we
decided we'd hitch up to LA and see what
the temple wasn't about and probably was
just arriving and everybody was just in
a tussle getting ready for property to
come I was still a hippie I had long
hair and a beard but the devotee said I
think I could go down to the flowers the
flower market and I could get some
flowers I can make a garland for a prop
odd and so improper came I made a
garland and he got off the airplane and
walked out to the car and I bowed down
and I put the flowers around real
prophets nag and bent down and touched
his feet and you look down and said and
then so when will you be joining I
really didn't have an intention to join
then but I knew the way you looked into
my eyes that I would be joining soon
when the AIA I went back I went back to
Laguna many devoted friends who were
there - alia - alia was a god sister and
she was there Michelle you was she was
to me was one of the most mystic girls
I've ever met in my life
she was so spiritually minded and knew
everything about bhagavad-gita she could
preach so nicely so the whole time I was
living in Laguna I was going down to San
Diego to the self-realization fellowship
and all the people that lived there
although they all seemed nice and
sincere they they had hairdos like my
mother dead you know coming home from
the beauty parlor you know and they just
did not have the vibration to attract me
to a yoga lifestyle
whereas when I came to the temple all
the devotees were full of life and you
could tell that there was something
happening in them they were exuberant
with the devotional set sentiment
almost almost intoxicate caming to be
around them and you just wanted to know
what it was that they could have plugged
into that could have transformed their
life and made them feel so blissful and
while there wasn't anything lacking on a
mundane level in my life there was
something lacking deep in my heart and I
didn't feel complete and I felt a
yearning and that is what that is what
made the difference between other things
that I might have been looking at versus
my encounter with the devotees and so
then I went up to San Francisco made the
transaction met with Bob Rubin I went
down to the temple and went up to attend
Artie on to doodle is doing kirtan and I
want to do the was just ecstatic yurt
our leader and I saw the love of time to
do it immediately I accepted him as my
other guard brother and he had had a lot
of association with proper and could
just tell the most nectarine stories
about prop bud and so I shaved my head
that day and I joined the temple so that
was how I became a devotee what happened
was that George Harrison had given the
manor to the London devotees and there
was a shuffling around of personnel
improper wanted and proper wanted
constituted him avati to go to San
Francisco
well the Berkeley temple was so nude
there was no initiated devotees in the
Berkley temple so probably see is there
anyone suitable and honestly they said
yes there's one boy bhakta bill he would
be okay and so probably should already
sent him down and get him initiated and
so I flew down with a couple of what I
think four other devotees my wife I
believe low trying hard i nan de and we
all got initiated and that the
initiation robert explained that my
devotee named
was bahu Lhasa and he described that
bottle Lhasa was a king and he was a
great devotee of Krishna and he was
renowned for having many horses and he
said you have always had many horses and
always will have many horses and
therefore I give you this name many
horses and I grew up my family raised
and trained horses and all through my
adult life I had horses and even now as
I'm approaching in my life I still have
one horse that showed me that probably
was no ordinary person in my life and
that there are numerous instances when
probably read my mind where I was going
to see Shula proper and I've been
fretting about something or been in
anxiety and probably says so boy I saw
you've been thinking this and he would
know exactly what I had been thinking
and then I said would say yes your table
and then he said have you worked out the
solution and I would say no she'll
probably then he would say then I
recommend you do this what wasn't you
saying right who can do that to you you
know and so then what surely happened
and this was a giant boon from me this
was a boner and I do not want to present
this and a way to glorify myself because
it was all profits grace
and I just happen to be in the right
place at the right time so I had no
college education III did not even think
of myself as an intellectual person and
here I was a temple president of Berkley
temple and for some reason one day this
gentleman came to the temple on Durant
and he was dr. Stillson Judah and he was
a head of the Berkeley Theological
Seminary and he told me he wanted to
compile a book about Krishna
consciousness and specifically what
makes a person become a devotee and so I
told them I asked properly but if I
could get permission and probably said
yes give him permission and so this
began a two-year project where we put
together questionnaires about background
what were your thoughts like before so
and so forth and we submit additional
problem he was very pleased with it and
dr. Judah went ahead and published his
books and he derived great notoriety for
doing this book was the first of its
kind and he derived great notoriety and
became very intimate with your problem
and because because of my contact like a
liaison between him every time for all
but one is he
dr. dr. Judah he would invite me down on
one of these walks with dr. Judah Sheila
proper was explaining that the way to
become Krishna conscious is through
practice the practice of devotional
service of sadhna and that if you don't
practice getting up in the morning going
to Aarti chanting Trivandrum geared to
them all the various ways to practice
devotional service then there's no
question of you becoming Krishna
conscious you can't become Krishna
conscious without engaging in the
activities of devotional service and so
I made some kind of comments some kind
of foolish comment come out of my mouth
about the importance of this or that
ensure a proper turned around and told
me that he had been explained this to me
for a hundred lifetimes and all of the
bodies went oh
as if that was a compliment that
properties had to come back a hundred
times to save me from ignorance but
profit actually meant at least I took it
in a way that this is how foolish you
are that after a hundred lifetimes
you're still not getting the message
that Krishna consciousness has to be
practiced can you say like that any
settings that's already yet maybe you
have not seen it but I've seen God
that is quite possible because we have
not scooted and it studied all the men
of the world yes then how we can say
nobody has said you have not seen the
man who are sinning
so they will not admit his fault he
accuse Aras nobody else in it what you
may not have seen but why you say no
Deus you have not seen that person who
has seen one
therefore you select
so the those people who wrote the Bible
never did not see God
[Music]
that is when God is canvassing yeah
Krishna day let's eat and he still there
Robert you see now there's a few quick
instances but before I would jump to
them I would note that my dearest
dearest God brother and friend who
passed away just a few years ago
darling Joshua I joined the movement and
where I may have excelled in
organizational skills Dharma excelled in
academic skills and Dharma was able to
Dharma was able to take the entire
university curriculum and decipher it so
that we could have a class not just in
religious studies or a class in
archaeology and Hindu sociology and so
where I was where I had a robust college
program you know lecturing once or twice
a week Dharma with his brilliance turned
that into easy go to the University you
do three or four lectures at a time and
so it was it became a giant program we
made lots of devotees Kevin joined on
the basis of that and so the next
professor I got to meet was dr. Theodore
Rose AK and he was he was a I would say
a bigger intellectual
then doctor and shooter was and he
wanted to write a book the making of the
counterculture and so doctor dr. Julie
introduced him to me and I flew down to
said to LA and introduced him to brow
paws and somehow or other I became I
became the liaison person between the
professors and proper okay so dr. Rose
ACK and dr. Judah had different slants
okay dr. Rose Jack was the intellectual
and dr. Judah was more like an
administrator and so those conversations
took different twists and dr. Rose act
even though he would be sometimes
challenging to prappas view he was
always always highly respective of
Prabhas view and prophet had different
themes different themes that he would
discuss with these professors and one of
the themes that he discussed was life
comes from life and so this topic life
came comes from life this topic dr. Rose
act latched on to okay and he saw in
this a he saw in this a topic that he
could actually
make a mark in okay and he wrote a book
called the voice of the earth now the
premise of this book is very deep and I
won't go into it in his full scope well
I've read it a dozen times myself
so the idea is this how did the universe
come into being so let's not approach
this with any kind of bias okay let's
say that neither of us know how the
universe came into being right well we
have all this data and we're going to
try to compile this data and see if we
can indeed make some sense out of it so
yes so this is it here so you can see
how many times they're ready to that
cover is coming on and so the very first
notion that some whack ball scientists
put forth was that randomness who
described the evolution of life and the
idea the the kind of joke if you would
that they put together was if you put
together a million monkeys in a room
and they all typed away eventually they
would produce DNA that was their idea
and if the and so the premise on this is
if you had an infinite period of time
and because when this was proposed don't
believe how old the universe was so you
couldn't really debate it because give
it an infinite amount of time anything's
possible right certainly you know I mean
an infinite amount of time is just you
can't get your head around what an
infinite amount of time is well then as
that theory evolved the German who
calculated this is in this book it
became apparent there wasn't an infinite
amount of time the universe had a life
span thirteen and a half billion years
sounds like a lot of time right for the
pales in comparison to infinite and so
he's shown that there is not adequate
time for the monkeys to generate DNA and
typer and typing randomly
so he and Sheila prob pod Rosic put that
forth is said to show up Robert what do
you think of this idea now in light of
the thirteen and a half billion years
when I think just was not a morning walk
and probably said obviously that
thirteen billion and incident are not
the same and therefore it would be
impossible that such a thing could come
about and then rose like bid into that
and that became that got published in
this book and that became one of his
major lecturing points one thing that
stands out to me on a on a very intimate
note or Rafi archers and you know San
Francisco temple is do drug enough pours
that's what probably called it from the
beginning all the devotees who have
served there for any length of time
worship sugar that's in that spirit and
I love jogging the temple like I love
joking us forward and shield proud was
coming up to do what was called mantra
rock now there really wasn't a big
temple there yet but Allen Ginsberg who
wrote the introduction to bhagavad-gita
was convinced seekers organize a big
kirtan and so I was own initiative
Ellen organised mantra rocked and all
the famous rock bands of the day played
janis joplin played you you just name it
they were there and there was a giant
success it really gave the feeling that
this gun was just going to now explode
and the very really gonna be holding
point and Country Joe and the fish were
there and this was a great event that it
was held as a family dog and the next
year we had another festival there I
didn't attend the mantra rock festival I
still a hippie on again but I attended
the second one and Nara na Ryan had
built the karts and we pulled them
through Golden Gate Park and proper
danced and proper danced it was like the
whole universe danced everyone went to
pure ecstasy was just magnificent and
when it was over Marley had rented a
vehicle some kind of a limo to pictural
profit up and takes your problem back to
the apartment that we were rented for
him
and when we got to the car I was
standing behind bottle Shila problem
with sitting a passenger side with his
legs on the ground and lot of Issa was
kneeling like this and he said did you
like his little problem
he'll probably grab me supplied the head
hands on his head and kissed and kissed
him
he said I loved it model visa that was
just no it's just another endearing
moment where I realized who the Guru was
what the real Joker guru was the aspect
that I had not seen before was the
intimacy was the loving sentiment that
the Guru has with the disciple it was
not simply some mechanical thing where
he came and like at a church made a
donation went away but there was a deep
bond of love between the Guru and the
disciple and then all you had to do was
engage in devotional service and you can
experience that directly for yourself
and so then we decided we were going to
do a Roth er I mean a Lord chain Tania
Festival and lo chat das was a great
artist he had been in the Berkeley
temple you joined before I did
he created the mercies of Lord Chaitanya
and they were life-sized and we paraded
them down the street and they moved in
their arms move and we then culminated
that at at People's Park and probably it
was very pleased with that event and
[Music]
encouraged us to continue doing more
festivals and then and then issue upon
Ishod came out up until then we had been
just distributing back to Godhead within
the issue a partnership I came out so
hurry and I dine on then I we went out
in the evenings just the two of us and
distribu show up on Ishod and that was
very nice proper was really pleased with
that and then there was a practice where
different devotees would have the
opportunity to be probably servant for
some period of time and so usually a
problem would be travelling they might
be stopping at you know some temple and
you have an opportunity would there be a
window of time you have an opportunity
to go to be probably servant and so
problem was coming to New Bern da band
and there was a couple of weeks where no
one was designated to be his servant and
so I was offered the opportunity to do
that and so I was delighted and I took
it immediately and I bet I paid for our
party and would massage him with mustard
oil and rub sanded with face on his head
and sit next to him and span and itself
was very hot a new wind of it and one
night I was getting probably his bed
ready and I laid out all his sleeping
power Fidelia and probably was looking
out the window and he had a giant tulsi
said the toasting peacock feather that
has fallen from you know from worth it
is whis and he bent down and picked it
up and he began holding it over his face
and it was just chanting gold and
[Music]
Bravo just became so overwhelmed with
ecstasy and I was just I was just the
world you know what to think or what to
say anything it was so touching and so
intimate
I was actually embarrassed it was as if
I had walked in on something very
intimate and should not have been even
engaging at it and then I picked up a
few other artifacts as falling in saying
that show progress room and when he was
finished then then I offer my humble
obeisances and walked away and there
were many instances where prophets
showed that his knowledge of Krishna was
not simply coming out of books what is
knowledge impersonal was based on the
fact that he knew personal when he
invokes firstly it was personal and then
we were in the process of getting a
temple in Chicago and I had saved up
Lakshmi to buy the building
[Music]
it was very hard doing sankirtana in
Chicago because it was the median
capital of the world it was very demonic
and the winters were horrible and and
the luxury was thin and lean yes when I
first got there we had no water when my
name was threw me was pregnant we went
through the whole winter with no water
no hot water then a blessing from heaven
came horrible Jacques Acharya and part
of my honza to Brahma cherries from
Colorado arrived out of the blue and
they were there were such great Souls
they were so much fun so enthusiastic
never got tired and they just
revitalized my meager efforts and we
finally raised the money and my gone to
I got two new endowment to tell probably
you know that we raised the funds and
[Music]
Sasa roof I've gone there before me he
was GBC when he insisted on another
building
that was a YMCA building and so he was
there for three or four days selling
probably how great type building was but
in my mind it was nothing but a headache
well when I got there was too late
problems was convinced we're going to
get that building this old and Suzi eyes
they go bald ah so so you've found the
building so big and what was I gonna say
right never said yes so we got that
building but I was always looking for an
opportunity to get out of there as
quickly as I could
and then finally chazuke Ananda Jitsu
Gironda I gone to I gone to Mexico City
and profits in your help and we were
friends
and so Chizu kindly invited me there and
then probably came to Mexico City oh my
god you could not believe that man it
was the Pope coming to Mexico City the
Mexican people are so devoted you know
it is just it's just Lawsons from their
heart and their reception - she'll
probably was just amazing just amazing
and many many mayors
of towns and you know County ships and
stuff right what it probably come to
speak you know the q and A's were we're
not really philosophically profound as
much as they were love of God directed I
think that's what stood out mostly there
weren't doubters you know there weren't
there weren't oh oh why the you know
there was any of that there was they saw
probable part you know they saw who he
was they knew who he was and it was just
more take sheltered probably slow to see
and you know that kind of just loving
devotion well the most attractive
quality the most undeniable quality is
unalloyed devotion this I've never seen
in another human being
okay never seen anything like it
real love of God and they're you know
they're being due to my false ego you
know there have been little tweaks and
things here where I might have had got
puffed up and had some ego difference
you know between how this could be or
that could be philosophically you know
the mouth to anything they don't even
come close to the devotional sentiment
that you encounter when you see field
problems and when you're wearing this
services show problem I want to offer my
humble is no base is this - my god
brothers and God sisters who I've had
the good fortune to know and to social
profile in this life
thank you all problems and properties
Oh glory soprano glories to lord
caitanya
[Music]
right true
don't know
[Music]
you